Eloy Gonzalez

Woodstock, GA ~ 404.993.6698 ~ eloy522752@gmail.com ~ LinkedIn Profile ~ GitHub ~ Portfolio

Sr. Software Architect & Systems Programmer

A high energy and multi-faceted professional offering 17+ years of progressive leadership expertise in enterprise software development and systems programming in supporting a diverse client base. Possesses in-depth experience in user interface (UI) design, information architecture, and user personalization. Exceptional relationship-building skills and well-versed in all phases of the software development life cycle, including requirements gathering, design, data flows, prototyping, usability testing, development, and code testing.

Bilingual, fluent in English and Spanish

Key Leadership Skills & Technical Expertise

- ✓ Application & Information Architecture
- ✓ Leading Organizational Transformations
- ✓ Strategic Planning and Tactical Execution
- ✓ Business Analysis and Business Intelligence
- ✓ End-to-End Program and Project Management
- ✓ Integrating Technology and Business Objectives
- ✓ Building, Mentoring, and Leading Technical Team
- ✓ Software and Hardware System Integration
- ✓ Database and Applications Management
- ✓ Quality Assurance (Unit Testing, Linting, Continuous Integration)

- ✓ Server Side Development (MERN Stack, Progressive Web Applications)
- ✓ Data Center Design and Implementation
- ✓ Customer Relationship Management
- ✓ Third-party / Server API Integrations
- ✓ Software Systems Design
- ✓ User Interface Design
- ✓ GIT / GitHub Deployments
- ✓ IIS Server Administration
- ✓ Custom Functions
- ✓ Technical Sales

.Net 4.0, .Net 4.5, Access, AJAX, API, ASP.Net Programming, Bootstrap, CSS, C#, Heroku, HTML5, Infor CRM, JavaScript, JSON, jQuery, Mongo DB, MS Flow, MySQL, Node JS, PowerApps, REST services, Sage CRM, Salesforce, SQL, SQL Server, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Windows Forms, Windows Server

Professional Experience

J.M. HUBER CORPORATION – Atlanta, GA

Aug 2006 - Oct 2020

<u>Sr. Enterprise Solution Developer</u> (Nov 2018 – Oct 2020)

Enterprise Solutions Developer (July 2012 – Nov 2018)

<u>CRM Programmer, Analyst</u> (Aug 2006 – July 2012)

Promoted multiple times with increasing leadership responsibility, serving as a vital member of the software development team. Provides ongoing support to CCR HEM.order integrations and applications. Recognized for leading the team in completing multiple strategic initiatives, including:

- Helped CPK initial/mid-SalesLogix data migration efforts to Salesforce, assisted in the successful HEM data center move for SalesLogix.
- Integrated internal API document generation for reports called from different cloud systems (REST services).
- Worked with Cloud PowerApps to print labels from local Dymo printers for HEM plants. Azure API Apps, Azure Logic apps, Azure Functions, Power Query)
- Provides CRM global day-to-day end-user support (including system configuration, complex formulas, and system maintenance) and assists users with best practices to increase Salesforce.com knowledge.
- Maintains CRM user roles and profiles, security settings, and access settings (user profiles, role hierarchy, sharing rules, and security).

- Hands-on experience in mass data migrations using various data migration tools.
- In-depth expertise with integrating 3rd party apps with Salesforce, production deployment, responding to production support requests, and troubleshooting.
- Perform data integrity and manipulation tasks, including merging duplicate records and establishing proper ownership of existing accounts and contacts within sales territories.
- Established and implemented best practices regarding system maintenance, configuration, development, testing, and data integrity.
- Designs, documents, builds, tests, and deploys enhancements to CRM objects, page layouts, workflows, alerts, reports, and sophisticated dashboards; develops and implements web page interfaces.
- Creates ASP.NET pages using C#.NET for middle-tier processing of client requests with ADO.NET interfaces for database and implemented stored procedures.
- Leverages ADO.NET and data objects such as Data Adapter, Data Reader, Dataset, and Data Table for consistent access to SQL data sources; develop custom error pages and error handling.
- Implemented appropriate WinForms error handlers to ensure users can experience user-friendly messages for exceptions.
- Developed stored procedures, triggers, and views in SQL Server 2008 for accessing the database.
- Migrated the functionality from existing ASP pages to new ASPX pages, adding new features to reflect the business user's requirements; implemented Session State Management.
- Active participant in collaborative meetings with business users and project teams to ensure volatile business requirements are reflected in the project development.

AIG AGENCY AUTO – Atlanta, GA

March 2004 - Aug 2006

CRM Programmer, Analyst

Challenged to work collaboratively with clients and the implementation team to gather and interpret user and system requirements into design specifications. Researched, evaluated, and recommended solutions and appropriate technology to meet the client's application needs.

- Arranged project requirements in programming sequence by analyzing requirements; prepared a workflow diagram using knowledge of computer capabilities, subject matter, programming language, and logic.
- Applied system-analyst techniques and procedures, including consulting with users to determine hardware, software, or systems functional specifications.
- Designed, developed, documented, analyzed, created, tested, and modified computer systems, programs, and integrations.

PRAXI SOLUTIONS, INC. – Atlanta, GA **Programmer, Analyst**

Oct 2001 – March 2004

Community Affiliations

Certified, personal GroupEx (group exercise) trainer with a history of working in the health wellness and fitness industry. Teach weekly GroupEx classes at local YMCAs that include *Strong Nation*, *Zumba*, and *Zumba Kids*. An active participant in annual Spartan Races.

Education

GA Institute of Technology (GA Tech) – Atlanta, GA: Full stack Developer Bootcamp

Florida International University (FIU) – Miami, FL: Bachelor of Arts Degree (BA), Business Administration Minor in Management Information Systems (MIS)

Miami Dade College - Miami, FL: Associates of Arts Degree (AA), Business Administration